Celebrating over 2 million copies sold
TV anime adaptation confirmed!
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing
Original: 3rd Girls'
Fighter Wing
Director:
Kinoshita
Seiichi
Written by: Mai
take Shimeji
Character Design:
Iguchi Yumi
Animation
Production:
Musashino
Animation
Fourseasons Aria: Suzuki Kyouko
Catherine: Itou Suzuka
Tatiana: Tokiwa Hiroko
Noa: Asagami Eri
Christine: Makise Ayano
Grief in the Shell
My harem might be falling apart,
but I guess I'm just imagining things
Ekaterina
of
the
Danzig
Corridor
Ekaterina
of
the
Danzig
Corridor
Ekaterina
of
the
Danzig
Corridor
It's finally been made public!
（安藤(あんどう)）
いよいよ情報解禁されましたね！
It says "Produced by Musashino Animation"!
“制作 武蔵野(むさしの)
アニメーション”って出てます
Yeah, and people are all like
"Musani? lolwat?" and "Musani's still a thing?"
（太郎(たろう)）
うん 出てる“ムサニかよ”
“ムサニ まだあったんだ”って
"Kinoshita's the guy who directed BoingPara, right?"
“監督は あの「ぷる天」の木下(きのした)”
“キャラデの井口(いぐち)って誰？”
"Who's this Iguchi on character design?"
"Never heard of the MC's voice actor."
“主役の声優 知らない子”
Stop reading just the negative comments, Takanashi-san!
（あおい）
ネガティブな反応ばっかり
拾わないでください 高梨(たかなし)さん！
The character designs got approved and production has started.
キャラデもオーケーになって
やっと現場も動きだしたし
The schedule might be rough, but let's make this happen!
スケジュールは厳しいけど
頑張りましょう！
Yeah!
（安藤･佐藤）はい！
（太郎）俺も頑張る～！
I'm so in!
All the other main characters' designs were approved too!
（あおい）
残りのメインキャラも
全員オーケーもらいました！
Awesome!
（井口）
やった！
Thank you, Ogasawara-san!
I couldn't have done this without you.
小笠原(おがさわら)さんのおかげです
ありがとうございます！
No, not at all. It is thanks
to your unwavering efforts.
（小笠原）
いえ 井口さんがめげず腐らず
頑張ったからです
Then I'll get started with the other characters and on with the AD work too.
じゃあ 他のキャラにも手つけるね
作監作業にも入るから！
Thank you!
お願いします！
Where am I...
You've changed so much.
（興津(おきつ)）見違えましたね
（本田(ほんだ)）そうですか？
Have I?
What happened? Got yourself a missus?
（太郎）
どうしちゃったんすか
色気づいたんすか？
If only.
（本田）
んなわけないだろ
いや 自分では自覚全然…
I don't even notice it myself.
Honda-san!
本田さん？
Ah, Miyamori! Hi there!
ああ 宮森(みやもり)さん お疲れ
You've lost so much weight!
（あおい）
痩せすぎじゃないですか
Not being out of ideas all the time must help.
万策尽きることが
ないからじゃない？
So you were fat because of the stress?
ストレス太りだったんすか
I'm living on a proper daily schedule now too.
（本田）
規則正しい生活してるしな
This is Honda-san, the previous PM.
うちでデスクをやってた本田さん
He now works at a confectionery called Ururin.
今はウルリンっていう
ケーキ屋さんで働いてて
A confectionery?
（佐藤）ケーキ屋さん
（安藤）なんかすごい
Wow.
I brought some too.
これ差し入れ
（あおい）
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
Ah, director! Long time no see.
（本田）
あっ 監督　お久しぶりです
What are you doing here?
（木下）
何しに来たんだよ
Not to mention you lost so much weight...
（木下）
しかも
そんなに一人で痩せちゃって
What happened to the Extra Fat Alliance?!
俺たちの余分な脂肪同盟は
どうしたんだよ？
I don't remember joining anything like that.
そんな同盟 組んだ覚えはないです
I guess I left all my extra weight here at Musani.
それに俺の脂肪は
このムサニに置いていきました
You're not allowed to make it sound that cool!
カッコよく言ってもダメ！
同盟は解消だな！
You're out of the alliance!
There never was such a thing in the first place.
だから そんな同盟結んでませんよ
He brought us some sweets too!
本田さんがケーキ持ってきて
くださったんですよ
It'll make me fat! Do not want!
（木下）
太るから いらない！
There's some Mont Blanc too.
（本田）
モンブランもありますよ
おひとつ どうぞ
Sure you don't want one?
Can I have two?
（木下）
２個食べていい？
You too.
（本田）
きみたちも どうぞ
Yay!
（佐藤）ありがとうございます
（安藤）いただきます
Thank you!
I'll help myself!
（太郎）
いただいてます！
I see you haven't changed, Takanashi.
相変わらずだな 高梨は
確かによく驚かされます
He definitely keeps us on our toes.
He's always contradicting himself too.
言ってることが
コロコロ変わりますからね
Andou, Satou-san, you're starting to sound more and more like Miyamori.
（太郎）
安藤 佐藤さん
ツッコミが宮森に似てきたな～
お前に似なくてよかったよ
Well, at least they're not sounding like you.
Of course they're not! I'm too irreplicable, unique, and special for that!
（太郎）
まあ 俺は 誰にもマネができない
唯一無二の存在なんで
ある意味そうです
In a way, yeah.
I'll go retrieve some ups.
（安藤）じゃあ回収に行ってきます
（あおい）うん
I'll be going too!
（佐藤）
私も行ってまいります
Good, the new PAs seem to have their heads on straight.
しっかりした子が入ってよかったな
Yeah.
はい
Wasn't there one more though?
もう一人
入ったんじゃなかったっけ？
（あおい）
ああ 平岡(ひらおか)さんですか
Ah, Hiraoka-san?
実はあまり会社にいなくて
He doesn't come in much.
You shouldn't hold back just because he's got experience. Say what needs to be said.
ベテランだからって
遠慮しないで―
言うべきことは言ったほうがいいよ
（あおい）はい
Got it.
Director, the art meeting starts soon.
Finish that in five minutes.
（あおい）
監督 この後 美打ちなんで
５分で食べてください
Next, the scene in episode 3 with the ruins.
（木下）
次は３話の廃虚のシーンですね
無残なんだけど美しくて
It should be tragic yet beautiful all at once.
I'd like backgrounds that can make you tear up.
見ただけで泣ける
廃虚にしたいんだよね
It's Aria's hometown after all.
ありあのふるさとなんで
What kind of ruins would that be?
（渥美(あつみ)）
どんな雰囲気の廃虚ですか？
A ruined city that you'd expect from Ookura-san.
（木下）
例えば
大倉(おおくら)さんが描いた廃虚みたいな
You sure set the bar high there.
それは またハードルが高いですね
Ookura-san? Who's that?
（あおい）
大倉さんって誰ですか？
（渥美）えっ？
（木下）えっ 知らない？
You don't know?
The art director of Neighborhood Space Squad
and Gekitopa II, among others.
「町立宇宙軍」とか
「劇トパⅡ(ツー)」の美術監督
あっ 両方とも見ました！
すごかったですよね
I've seen both of those! They're really amazing!
Even the birds'-eye views of those backgrounds were so powerful!
情感があって
しかも迫力がある背景でした
I'd love to just ask him to do it all.
（木下）
あ～ いっそのこと
大倉さんに頼めないかな
I'm afraid I'm not nearly
well-known enough to ask him.
とてもじゃないけど
巨匠すぎて僕から頼めません
Me neither...
（木下）
俺だって…
Then should I?
私 頼んでみます
You would?!
（木下）マジ？
（あおい）頼むのはタダですから
It never hurts to ask.
You're a fearless one.
怖いもの知らずだな
Is he really scary or something?
（あおい）
えっ そんなに怖い方なんですか？
He's not too easy to get along with,
and getting him to accept a job isn't a cakewalk either.
…つか 気難しくて
なかなか
仕事受けてくれない人みたい
It's definitely worth a try, though.
でも チャレンジしてみてくれると
うれしいな
Then I'll figure out how to contact him.
じゃあ連絡先 調べてみますね
A promotional video?! Now?!
Fatal Fat
Talkative Service
（葛城(かつらぎ)）
えっ プロモーションビデオ？
今からですか？
Did I forget to tell you?
（茶沢(ちゃざわ)）
あれ～
お伝えしてなかったですっけ？
We'll be screening it at our company booth at ManFes.
うちの社のブースで流すんですけど
マンフェスの
ManFes?!
（葛城）
マンフェス…
You know, the Manga Festival! It's on the 13th of August.
（茶沢）
やだな～
マンガフェスティバルのことっすよ
８月13日からの
（葛城）
それは知ってます
でもＰＶを流すっていうのは…
I know what it is.
But I didn't hear about a PV...
おっかしいな～
言ってるはずなんだけどな
That's weird. I'm sure I told you.
Funny thing is, it's a chance to show the world what you're made of at Musani.
変な話 ムサニの本気とやらを
見せてくださいね
Cheers!
よろしく～
（通話が切れた音）
ああ… 聞いてないよね　ねっ？
No one told you either, right? Right?
No.
（渡辺(わたなべ)）
ないです
What do we do? What do we do?!
（葛城）
どうする？　どうする？
We don't really have a choice. We're making it.
どうするって 作るしかないでしょ
We're now officially in a state of emergency.
ムサニ非常事態宣言です
This has gotten ugly.
（丸川(まるかわ)）
こりゃ大変だね
We only have a little over two weeks until ManFes!
（あおい）
マンフェスまで あと
２週間ちょっとしかないんですけど
And they want us to deliver by the 9th,
so make that 13 days.
（渡辺）
８月９日には完パケにしろと
言われてるから
正確には あと13日
What do we do?
（あおい）
どうしたら…
Just use dummies!
（平岡）
ダミー ダミー
もう作業に入ってるカットを
Patch together cuts that are already done and call it a day.
適当に見繕って
つなげればいいんだよ
But this'll be the first video to go public, right?
でも初めて世に出る映像ですよね
I want Aria's cuteness to overwhelm everyone!
（安藤）
かわいく動くありあを
みんなに見てほしいです！
PVs are just another pain in the ass.
ＰＶなんて余計な作業なんだからさ
Just do it in a way that puts the least burden on the staff.
現場に負担かけないように
そこそこでいいんだよ
But... But it'll influence everyone's expectations for the show.
でもさ でもさ お客さんの
作品への期待値も変わるし
If we do it, we do it right.
作るんなら
しっかりしたもの見せないとな
That's right! Let's show them what we're all about!
（太郎）
そうだ そうだ！
ムサニの本気を見せるんすよ！
Miyamori, bring me the storyboards up to episode 4.
宮森 ４話までのコンテ
持ってきてくれる？
Katsuragi-san and I are gonna pick the PV cuts.
葛城さんと俺でカット選ぶから
G-Got it!
はい！
PV?
（ミムジー）
ＰＶって何？
It stands for promotional video.
（ロロ）
プロモーションビデオのことだよ
The Abusive Duo, Mimuji and Lolo!
The Abusive Duo
Mimuji
&
Lolo
I'm Mimuji, a descendant of vikings and pirates!
（ミムジー）
私はミムジー
バイキングか
パイレーツの末えいよ！
I'm Lolo! My crooked moon mark doesn't bother me anymore.
（ロロ）
僕はロロ
ズレてる月の輪なんて
もう気にしない！
We're not real, but we're bursting with life in daydreams!
Probably on air in October!
多分 10月放送
Wish us luck!
（ミムジー･ロロ）
応援してね！
These are the priority cuts for the PV.
（あおい）
ＰＶ先行カット出ました
ighter Wing event PV cut list
Total
3rd Girls' F
ighter Wing event PV cut list
Total
So we should get these done first?
このカットを優先して
上げてもらうってことですか？
That's right. I lined up a schedule for the PV.
そう　ＰＶ用のスケジュール
引いてみたら…
Three days for the layouts and six for keyframes?
３日後にはレイアウトアップ
６日後には原画アップ
Nine days for tweens, tween checking, backgrounds, and color setting?!
９日後に動画 動画検査
背景 色指定アップ！
キツいっす これ
Wave the white flag.
I'll explain the situation to the departments.
各部署には私から説明しておくから
You should talk to the keyframers in charge of priority cuts,
先行カットを担当している
原画マンさんたちのところへ行って
tell them what's going on,
and ask for their cooperation.
事情を説明してお願いしてみて
That's so tough.
心苦しいです
We had them stall work until just a few days ago because of the character designs,
先日はキャラデの件で
作業を止めていただいたのに
and now we're rushing them?
今度は早く上げてくださいなんて
I know...
私もです
It's part of a PA's job to make the impossible possible sometimes!
制作ってのはな
時には無理を押し通すのも
仕事なんだよ！
Go, Andou, Satou!
Show us your PA negotiation skills!
行け 安藤 佐藤！
制作のネゴシエーション力を
見せる時だ！
Most of the priority cuts are from episode 1,
which is all yours, Takanashi-san.
高梨さんの担当の１話が
一番カット数多いです
Her room (dark)
Photo with her
deceased boyfriend
Zips her jacket
You want me to do this cut first?
（遠藤(えんどう)）
このカット 先に上げんの？
Please.
よろしくお願いいたします
I wanted to do the whole scene at once, though.
シーンで
まとめて出したいんだよな
Then just do the entire scene first.
では まとめて先に
出していただけますか？
That's insane!
ムチャ言うなよ！
Is that insane?
ムチャを言ってますでしょうか？
It is!
（遠藤）
ムチャだよ！
ああもう 宮森呼んで！
Just call Miyamori!
Okay. I will return shortly.
かしこまりました　では改めます
I will return once I've consulted my superior, Miyamori,
一度 上司の宮森と相談して
もう一度お願いに上がりますので
and ask for your assistance once again.
何とぞ よろしくお願いいたします
You know,
（新川(しんかわ)）
あのさ ＰＶ優先って言っても
I get that we're fast tracking the PV,
but the base colors haven't even been approved yet.
ベースカラーも まだ全部
オーケーもらってないのに
I can't just decide the scene colors myself.
シーンのカラー決めらんないよ
Then how about finishing the scene first and doing the base colors afterwards?
では シーンのカラーを決めた後で
ベースのカラーのほうに
取りかかっていただく
ということでいかがでしょうか？
はあ？　いや それ無理
できないから
Not happening. I can't do that.
Does that mean you quit?
（佐藤）
では お仕事を辞退される
ということで…
No, it doesn't!
そういうことじゃなくて！
I'm terribly sorry, but could you please explain it to me then?
申し訳ありませんが 順序立てて
説明していただけますか？
Get Miyamori to explain it to you.
宮森さんに
説明してもらってくれる？
I'm so sorry, but please treat this as a top priority.
すみません
優先よろしくお願いします
I'm not done with the concept art for this part yet.
まだ ここ 美術ボードも
上げてないんだけど
Then do the concept art, please!
（安藤）
じゃあ ボードを上げてください
I'll need to stall episode 1 for that.
だったら１話の作業
いったん止めるよ
Okay!
（安藤）はい
（渥美）えっ いいの？
Is that really okay?
Yeah!
（安藤）はい
（渥美）ああ…
Or is it not?
（安藤）あれ よくないんですか？
（渥美）はあ～
If it needs to be done, it needs to be done.
やらなければいけないのなら
やるしかないな
Anime production seems to be full of the unexpected.
なんだか
アニメーションの現場って
突発的に
いろんなことが起こりますよね
I know, right?
（安藤）
ですよね～
It pains me how nothing goes according to plan.
胃が痛いです
全然 予定どおりに
物事が進まなくて
Apparently this is how things go in this industry.
でもアニメ業界って
こういうものらしいですよ
I think you're fit for this job.
安藤さんは
この仕事向いてそうです
You too, Satou-san!
佐藤さんだって向いてますよ
You're orderly and polite.
きちんとしてるし 礼儀正しいし
Actually, there's something I'm really bad at that I still can't get used to.
実は私 いまだに慣れない
とっても苦手なことがあって
What's that?
（安藤）何？
（絵麻(えま)）あの すみません
Um, excuse me.
Yes?
（佐藤）
なんでしょう？
It's about a PV priority cut.
ＰＶ先行カットのことで
ちょっと質問が
But you don't have any priority cuts
from episodes 3 and 4.
安原(やすはら)さんのところには
３～４話の先行カット
なかったはずですけど
ああ いえ 私じゃなくて―
Ah, it's not mine. It's Kunogi-san's.
久乃木(くのぎ)さんが
（久乃木）あっ！
You know the scene where Aria brushes her teeth?
（絵麻）
ありあが歯を磨くシーン
あるでしょ？
Yes. And?
はい それで…
Bru—
Is there any setting for the brush?
歯ブラシの設定ありますかって
No, there isn't.
（安藤）
いえ ないです
You can just make it yourself.
それは久乃木さんが
作っていいんじゃないの？
（久乃木）ど！
（絵麻）どのくらい使ってるか？
How much she's used it?
Ah, how much the bristles are spread?
歯ブラシが
どのくらい広がってるか
It should be new since she just joined a new team.
新しい舞台に来たんだから
新しい歯ブラシ
使うんじゃないかな
How she brushes?
磨き方？
We should ask the ED about that.
それは演出さんに聞こうね
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました
We're at the same company,
but we've hardly talked at all recently.
同じ会社にいるのに
最近なかなか
ゆっくり話す機会がないね
It's been a while since we last walked home together too.
一緒に帰るのも久しぶりだよね
Seriously...
（みどり）
ですよね
It feels like I haven't seen Zuka-chan-senpai and Mii-chan-senpai for ages.
ずかちゃん先輩と
みーちゃん先輩には
もう随分会ってないような気が
また みんなで集まりたいね
We should get together sometime.
じゃあ日曜の夜 集まろっか
Yeah, how about this Sunday?
（みどり）
たまにはうちの部屋提供しまっす！
I offer my place for this great cause!
Studio
Canabun
（中垣内(なかがいと)）
おっ 藤堂(とうどう)さん いいね
Toudou-san, the tires on the jeep look great!
そのジープのタイヤ
I used to make nothing but tires at my previous job.
（美沙(みさ)）
前の会社で
ずっとタイヤをやってたんです
So it's your specialty?
じゃあ 得意分野だ
Incoming
Aoi Midori
Toudou Misa
Don-Don-Donuts Meetup
Sunday night,
my place.
Wanna come?
（しずか）
“僕 ウメブー！”
I'm Plumpy!
With Plumpy
Dance and Play
“梅干しが大好きなブタだうめ～”
I'm a plum-loving pig! Let's be plum friends!
“よろしくうめ～！”
（携帯電話のバイブ音）
Sub: Don-Don-Donuts Meetup
1 New Message
Rii-chan
Sub: Don-Don-Donuts Meetup
It's not quite finished yet, but it'll do for the PV.
（下柳(しもやなぎ)）
まだ完成はしてないけど
ＰＶで見せても恥ずかしくない
レベルにはしたから
Sorry about the crazy schedule.
（あおい）
すみません 無理言って
I'll make sure to brush it up for the airing.
（下柳）
本編までには
もっとブラッシュアップさせるよ
Thank you!
はい お願いします！
It's a fighter jet harness.
（みどり）
戦闘機のハーネスです！
（木下）
ディーゼルさん
どこで見つけてきたの？
Dr. Diesel, where did you get this?
I made it myself, based on pictures from the Internet.
いや これ 手作りです
ネット画像見て
Whoa.
（舞茸(まいたけ)）
えっ すごいな！
Would the animators be able to use this as reference?
作画の参考になりますかね？
Totally! Thanks!
うんうん 助かる
井口さんが喜ぶよ
Iguchi-san will be so happy.
俺 ちょっと着けてみていい？
Can I try it on?
Now that won't be any help.
それ 参考になりません
Aria (tanktop)
toothbrush, hair cream
（絵麻）
多分 これは
予備動作が足りないから
I'd say there isn't enough pre-action, and she doesn't really look surprised.
Make her appear more surprised
ED Aria
toothbrush
mob
PV Priority
PV
Priority
Musashino Animation
3rd Girls' Fighter Wing
ビックリしたお芝居に
ならないんだね
あっ 別に
怒ってるんじゃないからね
I'm not angry or anything!
I think it should be something like this.
多分 こんな感じだと思うよ
Here. Good luck!
（絵麻）
はい 頑張って
You can do it!
（絵麻）
頑張ってね～
（絵麻）ふう～
（杉江(すぎえ)）新しい原画の子
She's really attached to you.
That new keyframer girl.
随分 安原さんに懐いてるんだね
You think so?
（絵麻）
えっ そうですか？
It's not a bad thing, for both of you.
いいんじゃないかな
安原さんのためにも
You learn from teaching others too.
人に教えるということは
自分にも教えるということだからね
言葉にして伝えることで
改めて分かることもあるし
There are things you only realize when you put them into words.
And you can't explain something you don't understand yourself.
自分がちゃんと理解してないと
教えられないからね
（舞台監督）
ウメブーの中に入るヤツ
どうしたんだ？
Where's the guy who's supposed to play Plumpy?
He should be on stage already!
もう開演時間 過ぎてんぞ！
Should I tell them to wait a little more in Plumpy's voice?
（しずか）
あの“もう少し待って”って
ウメブーの声で説明しましょうか？
Sorry!
（係員）
すみません！　連絡が取れました
I finally got in touch with the actor!
Turns out he's caught a bad fever!
ウメブーのアクター
急に熱出したとかで
What do we do then? The kids are going crazy!
どうすんだよ！
子供たち 待ちくたびれてるよ！
Should I wear it?
（係員）俺 入りましょうか？
（舞台監督）お前は無理だろ
Physically impossible.
Then you, director?
（係員）
じゃあ 監督が
In that case, who's gonna direct?!
俺が入ったら
誰が指示を出すんだよ！
Should I do it?
（しずか）私 やりましょうか？
（係員･舞台監督）えっ？
いや ムチャだろ アクションやって
リアルタイムにセリフ言うなんて
Can you handle that?
Acting it out and giving the lines at the same time...
I'll try!
やってみます！
Hello, boys and girls!
（しずか）
みんな こんにちは　僕 ウメブー！
I'm Plumpy, the plum-loving pig!
梅干しが大好きな
ブタなんだうめ～！
Who wants to plum play with me?
Dance and Play
僕と一緒に遊びたい
お友達はいるうめ～？
It's great you're all so full of energ—
みんな元気いいうめ～！
I can't stand... What do I do?
立てない！　どうしよう
うめ～！　痛いよ～
起こしてうめ～
Plum! That hurt!
Help me stand up!
Everyone plummy help!
みんなも引っ張るうめ～！
Plummy thanks!
ありがとうめ～！
Let's dance the plum dance together!
一緒にウメブーダンス踊るうめ
We're done!
（しずか）
お疲れさまでした！
（舞台監督）
ありがとう　助かったよ！
Thank you so much! You saved the day!
I learned a lot too!
私も勉強になりました！
（舞台監督）
次もあったら
またお願いするからね
We'll be counting on you next time too!
I'll be glad to help!
よろしくお願いします！
（みどり）
うわ～ 久しぶりに
みんなそろいましたね
It's been so long since we could all get together!
Feels like ages.
（絵麻）
なんか懐かしい
Work's been nuts lately.
ずっと仕事バタバタしてたから
Same here for me.
私もです
I bet you're all busy.
みんな忙しいよね
10月番組でしょ「サンジョ」
3rd Wing's in October, right?
ちょっと ちょっと！
そんなに気を使わなくってよ！
Hey, now. No need to avoid the subject.
オーディション落ちたのは
残念だったけど
Yeah, it's too bad I failed the auditions, but I'll catch up to you evenplumally!
私も そのうち
みんなに追いつくうめ！
（絵麻）あっ ウメブー
（美沙）なんですか？　それ
Plumpy!
What's that?
A pickled, plum-nosed pig.
鼻が梅干しのブタ
Oh yeah, he looks so sour!
あ～！
あの酸っぱそうなブタ！
I played Plumpy on stage today.
今日 ちょっと
ウメブーの中に入ってきたんだ
I was drenched in sweat!
いや～ 汗だく
子供に転ばされたりもしたけど
The kids even knocked me down once,
but it was tons of fun!
楽しかったよ！
Sounds like you're working hard,
Zuka-chan-senpai.
ずかちゃん先輩 頑張ってるんすね
I hope you'll keep getting lots of good jobs.
ずかちゃんに いい仕事が
いっぱい来るようになるといいな
I'm sure today's will prove to be worth it too!
きっと今日の仕事も
役に立ちますよ！
（美沙）
私 今の会社で
ジープのモーションやってて
I was doing the motion for a jeep at work, and the boss said my tires looked great.
タイヤ褒められました
だから ムダなことは
ないんだなって思って
That's when I realized there's no such thing as a pointless job.
どんな経験が役に立つか
分かんないもんね
We can't know which experiences will prove useful later.
That's right!
確かにそうっす！
Did you get used to settings production too, Rii-chan?
（美沙）
りーちゃんも設定制作 慣れた？
Yeah! I'm learning a lot!
はい すっごい勉強になります！
The director thinks the world of you too.
（絵麻）
りーちゃん 監督さんに
重宝されてるもんね
Do you think we're all a bit closer to the Seven Divines?
みんな ちょっとだけ
近づきましたかね
「七福陣」に
Just a bit.
少しだけね
Well then, shall we?
じゃあ あれやりますか！
Don-don-donuts, let's go nuts!
（一同）
ドンドン ドーナツ
ど～んといこう！
We've got one more week until the deadline for the PV.
（あおい）
ＰＶの納品まで あと１週間です
I'm sure it won't be easy, but let's do our best!
大変だと思いますけど
頑張りましょう！
Let go get keyframes like a bulldozer!
おっしゃ～！
ブルドーザーのように
原画回収してくるぞ！
Also, there's been a change to a setting.
それから設定に関しての
変更事項があります
Please come to the meeting room to discuss emergency measures.
今から緊急対応の説明をしますので
会議室へ移動してください
（安藤･佐藤）
はい
Okay.
One of the cars is getting a checkup,
それと進行車ですが
１台は点検のため
and we're using the other to take cuts to storage,
so neither is available for three hours starting at noon.
もう１台は
倉庫にカット袋を運ぶので
12時から15時まで使えません
は～い
じゃあ 自転車で行ってくっか
Guess I'll go by bicycle then.
Do you have any questions?
他に何かありますか？
If not, the morning meeting is over.
なければ朝礼は以上です
Satou-san, are you okay?
佐藤さん 大丈夫？
Yes, I'm fine.
すみません 大丈夫です
It's about the effects on the eyes.
（あおい）
目の処理なんですが
撮影さんからの要望で
after
these lines
Filming staff are asking for the lines in the irises to be added.
瞳の線を入れてほしいとのことです
Lines in the irises?
瞳の線ですか
Now that you mention it, they're not there.
ああ 確かに 今 ないですね
That's gonna be annoying.
え～ 大変じゃん
Do you know what time
Hiraoka-san's gonna come to work?
平岡さん 今日 何時に会社入るって
言ってたか聞いてます？
Why would I? I'm not into dudes.
（太郎）
えっ 俺 男に興味ないから
そういう意味じゃないです！
That's not the point!
Hey.
（平岡）
お～っす
Hiraoka-san!
（あおい）平岡さん
（平岡）何？
What?
Could you please come to the morning meetings?
あの 朝礼には
出るようにしてほしいんですけど
Morning meetings are so pointless.
朝礼なんて意味ないでしょ
平岡さん 目の処理が変更になって
You don't know there was an emergency meeting about the change of eye effects, do you?
緊急会議があったことを
知らないですよね？
We had that after the morning meeting.
（あおい）
朝礼の後 会議だったんです
Then tell me that stuff afterwards, like you are now.
そんなの 後から教えてくれれば
いいじゃないですか
If everyone just showed up whenever they wanted,
I'd need to tell you all one by one.
みんながバラバラに出社したら
１人ずつに同じことを
伝えなくちゃいけなくなります
早急な情報の共有もできません
It'd slow our communications to a crawl.
（平岡）
一斉メールで
いいんじゃないですか？
Just send out an email to everyone then.
回収に行くんで 車使いま～す
I'm going to pick up some stuff. I'll be taking a car.
Both cars are unavailable right now.
（あおい）
今は２台とも 車使えません
Huh?
That was also in the meeting.
これも朝礼で…
分かりました あしたは出ますよ
All right, all right. I'll come tomorrow.
5 Days to Deadline
All the PV cuts from episode 1 have passed the AD!
（太郎）
ＰＶカット 俺の１話は
全部 作監アップしたぞ！
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
Where are Satou and Andou-san?
佐藤 安藤さんは？
They went to pick up keyframes.
Now that you mention it, they've been out too long.
最後の原画回収に
向かったんですけど
まだ帰ってこないですね
Hello?
Um, Miyamori-san?
（佐藤）
あの 宮森さん
Ah, Satou-san? What's up?
あっ 佐藤さん どうかした？
I...
（佐藤）
私…
What's wrong?
I hope you weren't in an accident!
（あおい）
どうしたの？　まさか事故？
Um...
（佐藤）
あの… 私 どこに
いるんでしょうか？
Where am I?
Huh?
I'm on my way back from picking up Tanaka-san's keyframes...
（佐藤）
田中(たなか)さんのところへ
回収に行った帰りなんですけど
Tanaka-san lives at Oizumi-Gakuen, right?
（あおい）
田中さんって大泉(おおいずみ)学園だよね？
On my way back, I accidentally got on the highway.
その後 間違えて
高速に乗ってしまって
And then my phone died too!
携帯も電池が切れていて
Which highway?
（あおい）
高速って外環？　関越？
The Gaikan? The Kan'etsu?
I don't know!
分かりません
What do you see nearby?
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
（あおい）
周りになんかない？
There's a soft-serve ice cream flag.
（佐藤）
ソフトクリームの看板が…
Anything else?
（あおい）
他には？
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
Black
Soft
Serve
（佐藤）
“嵐山(あらしやま)”って書いてあります
It says Arashiyama.
Arashiyama?
嵐山…
In Kyoto?
京都っすか？
Ah, apparently it's read Ranzan!
（佐藤）
あっ“らんざん”って
読むみたいです
Ranzan...
（あおい）
らんざん…
（太郎）
あっ 関越道だな
Ah, it's the Kan'etsu.
Get off at the Hanazono interchange and turn back.
（あおい）
じゃあ 花園(はなぞの)インターで降りて
上り線に入って
Don't worry, you'll be fine.
Just make it back here.
大丈夫　落ち着いて
ゆっくり帰ってきてね
Don't panic.
慌てちゃダメだよ
I'm so sorry...
（佐藤）
すみません
Satou-san's always so organized,
and then she pulls a silly stunt like this.
佐藤さん しっかりしているようで
抜けてんな～
On the other hand, I seem silly but kind of am too.
まあ 俺は抜けてるようで
抜けてんだけどさ
Don't analyze yourself.
自分で言わないでください
Andou-san
Incoming Call
Hello?
Hello! I'm so sorry!
（安藤）
あの すみません！
私 今 大月(おおつき)です！
I'm in Ootsuki!
Ootsuki?!
Ootsuki Stn.
（あおい）大月？
（太郎）今度は山梨かよ！
Now we've got one in Yamanashi?
I fell asleep on the train!
（安藤）
電車の中で寝ちゃって…
The keyframes?
（あおい）
えっ 原画は？
I've got them! They're fine!
あります 大丈夫です！
That's a relief!
よかった～
I'm so sorry! I'll head back now as fast as possible!
（安藤）
すみません！
これから急いで戻ります！
Okay!
（あおい）分かった
（太郎）電車の中 走ってこいよ！
Run in the train so you'll get here sooner!
I'm back!
（安藤）戻りました！
（佐藤）申し訳ありませんでした！
I'm so sorry!
Welcome back!
おかえり
まだ ごはん食べてないでしょ？
You haven't eaten yet, have you?
（佐藤･安藤）
はい！
Yeah!
Thanks for the meal!
（佐藤･安藤）
ごちそうさまでした
（佐藤）
私 実は すごい方向音痴で
I'm actually terrible with directions.
（安藤）
佐藤さんが苦手なのって
道を覚えることだったんだ
Oh, so that's what you're bad at!
はい…
Yeah...
I'm sorry for the trouble I caused too.
（安藤）
私もご心配をおかけしました
A tight schedule tires people,
and tired people make mistakes.
現場はスケジュールがタイトだから
疲れてると うっかりしちゃうね
でも そのうっかりを
ちゃんと覚えておいてね
Just be sure to learn from them.
Then I'm sure you'll be fine next time.
覚えておけば
次の失敗はないから
That's what Yano-san told me.
…って 私も矢野(やの)さんに言われた
Really?
（佐藤）そうなんですか？
（あおい）うん
Yeah.
You've made mistakes too?
（佐藤）
宮森さんも失敗したこと
あったんですか？
More than I could ever count.
もう失敗だらけだったよ
なんかパニックになっちゃって
I totally panicked too.
（佐藤）
そうだったんですか
Really?
Keep on learning, and it'll all work out
場数踏めば なんとかなるから
佐藤さんも安藤さんも！
for both of you, Satou-san, Andou-san.
Okay!
（安藤･佐藤）
はい！
Thank you very much!
（安藤）
ありがとうございます！
ED check done!
（あおい）
演出チェック アップ
AD done!
作監 アップ
３Ｄモーション アップ
3D motion done!
動画 アップ
Tweens done!
Tween check done!
動画検査 アップ
Backgrounds done!
背景 アップ
Coloring done!
仕上げ アップ
At the 3rd
Wing, the unit's
restroom
Light
source (1) ↓
room light
Items
A cell
Mirror
white overlight
撮影 アップ
Filming done!
Done! Done! Done!
あっぷ あっぷ あっぷ
PV finished
You sound like you're drowning.
なんだか溺れてるみたいだよ
But if things are getting done,
that means we're almost there!
（ロロ）
でもアップするってことは
終わりが近いってことだよね
PV Editing Day
Studio
Editing done!
（渡辺）
Ｖ編終了！
Thank god! We made it!
よかった 間に合った～
ああ 宮森 渡辺です
Miyamori? It's Watanabe.
Hey, yeah.
はいはい お疲れ
今 プレビュー終わりました
The preview just ended.
帰るんですか？
You're leaving?
The PM told me to go home early.
デスクに早く帰れって言われたんで
The president didn't mention our traditional floated noodles?
今日 恒例の流しそうめん やるって
社長が…
Not interested.
興味ないんで
We're screening the PV we just finished too.
Can you at least go for that?
あの 完成ホヤホヤの
ＰＶも流しますから
それだけでも見てってください
フフン… ほい！
ほい！
ほいっとくりゃ！
Gotcha!
ゲ～ット！
Ah, Hiraoka-san!
（太郎）
あれ 平岡さん いたんすか？
You were here?
Yeah.
（平岡）いたよ
（太郎）存在感ないっすね～
You've got so little presence.
お前ほどにはな
Unlike you.
Do I stand out that much?
（太郎）
えっ 俺
そんなにスター性あります？
まあ 飲みましょうよ～
Let's just drink
ＰＶの完成と―
to the completion of the PV and my bright future! 'Kay?
俺の輝かしい前途を祝して　ねっ！
（平岡）はあ？
Cheers!
かんぱ～い！
I just got the PV!
PV Finished
（あおい）
ＰＶ届きました～！
PV Finished
3rd Girls
Fighter Wing
ManFes PV
Musashino
Animation
Defying the vanishing skies
The story of five girls unfolds
I'm sorry, but no one from
production is available now.
Next time on Shirobako: "You Set Me Up Well!"
You Set Me Up Well!
（絵麻）
すみません
今 制作さんは誰もいません
次回「SHIROBAKO(シロバコ)」
（久乃木）
俺をはめやがったな！